Inventory of the Iris Chang papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Iris Chang papers
1877-2007
2004C22
Hoover Institution Archives
403 manuscript boxes, 4 cubic foot boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder (177.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, recordings and transcripts of interviews, photocopies of government records and other documents, printed matter, audiovisual material, and memorabilia relating to the history of Chinese in the United States, and to aspects of World War II. Includes research material for the books by Iris Chang, Thread of the Silkworm (New York, 1995), The Rape of Nanking (New York, 1997), and The Chinese in America (New York, 2003), and for an uncompleted work on conditions of American soldiers captured by Japanese forces and Japanese atrocities against American prisoners of war.
Chang, Iris.
Access
Boxes 377-379, 382-383, 386-394 and 397-412 closed until 2072 January 1. Remainder of the collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound and video recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view other videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual or digital material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
The material was acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004, with a substantial increment received in 2005. An additional increment was added in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1968 Born, Princeton, New Jersey
1989 Bachelor's degree, journalism major, University of Illinois
1991 Master's degree in writing, Johns Hopkins University
1992 Peace and International Cooperation award, John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation
1995 Author, Thread of the Silkworm
1997 Author, The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II
2003 Author, The Chinese in America: A Narrative History
2004 Died, California
Scope and Content of Collection
The Iris Chang papers span the career of a prominent American writer whose work centered on topics of Chinese and Chinese American history. In addition to speeches and writings, including drafts of her three books, the papers contain a large amount of research materials related to Chang's work as a historian. These include notes, interview transcripts, documents, sound recordings, and videorecordings. The collection also contains articles from Chang's career as a journalist, as well as significant biographical materials. There is a considerable amount of correspondence in the papers, including many letters of appreciation from readers of her books.
Chang's 1997 book The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II was an enormous popular success, focusing renewed attention on the actions of the Imperial Japanese army in China in the late 1930s and transforming Chang herself into a public figure who gave numerous speeches on the subject of her book. In the process, she became identified as an advocate who sought both to preserve the memory of the Nanking Massacre and to force a greater recognition on the part of Japan of its role in this tragedy.
Chang's other books include The Thread of the Silkworm, a biography of the Chinese rocket scientist Qian Xuesen (or Tsien Hsue-Shen), and The Chinese in America: A Narrative History, a major work on the Chinese American experience based on extensive research and interviews.
The collection contains numerous sound and video recordings of speeches made by Iris Chang, as well as of radio and television interviews conducted with her. Additionally, there are extensive materials in the papers relating to various public appearances made by Chang to promote her books. These include press releases, photographs, and correspondence.
The papers also contain materials pertaining to Iris Chang's death in 2004, including obituaries, memorial tributes, and letters of condolence received by her family.
World War, 1939-1945--Prisoners and prisons.; Prisoners of war.; World War, 1939-1945--Atrocities.; War crime trials--Guam.; World War, 1939-1945--Japan.; United States. Army.; Chinese Americans.; Qian, Xuesen, 1911-2009; Nanking Massacre, Nanjing, Jiangsu Sheng, China, 1937.; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945.; Audiotapes.; Video tapes.
- Open (Boxes 1-2)
- Subject file
  Scope and Contents note
  Clippings, correspondence, notes, and printed matter.
  - Recent Chinese smuggling, 1993-2000 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
  - Love Boat, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Eyelid surgery, 1982-1999 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Interracial marriages, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Chinese schools, 1997 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Beauty pageant, 2000 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Banana label, 1993 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Asian Greek system, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Asian Pacific Fund, 2000 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Angry Asian male, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - ASNE racism, 2001 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    Correspondence and clippings relating to the American Society of Newspaper Editors.
  - Future, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Babies, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Organized crime, 2000 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Lowell High School, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Sweatshops, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Human Rights in China (HRIC), 1998 (Box-folder 4: 10)
- Videorecordings
  - "Iris Chang: The Chinese in America,", 2003 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    One VHS videocassette
  - History Detectives, Public Broadcasting System, undated (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - "Committee of 100--Chinese American Identity,", undated (Box-folder 4: 13-14)
    Two VHS videocassettes
  - Committee of 100, 2003 Conference (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
  - Professor Amy Chua, undated (Box-folder 5: 3)
    Access
    Access DVD copy available for immediate viewing. Use reference ID 2004c22_002_r2015.
  - "Rape of Nanking" (Chinese version), undated (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - News program, KPIX TV, San Francisco, California, 2003 June 1 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - "The Rape of Nanking and the Goddess of Mercy," SIUC Radio-TV documentary, 2003 Spring (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - "China Doctor of Eastern Oregon and Journey into Spring,", undated (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Iris Chang interview, The Morning Edition, TV-31, Stillwater, Oklahoma, 2004 April 6 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    Access DVD copy available for immediate viewing. Use reference ID 2004c22_003_r2015.
- Sound recordings
  - Iris Chang interview, Forum, KQED radio, San Francisco, California, 2003 June 23 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c22_a_0011180
    One compact sound cassette
  - Iris Chang interviews, WNYC radio, New York, New York, 2003 April 28 and May 29 (Box-folder 6: 2-3)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c22_a_0011175
    Two compact sound cassettes
  - Iris Chang interview, David Pang program, KEST radio, San Francisco, California, undated (Box-folder 6: 4)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c22_a_0011181
  - Voice of America broadcast, 1997 June 8 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - "Chinese America: A History with Iris Chang," New Dimensions Foundation, Ukiah, California, 2003 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c22_a_0011182
  - Iris Chang radio interview, Houston, Texas, 2003 May 18 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c22_a_0011176
    One CD sound disc
  - "Iris Chang: The Chinese in America," Talk of the Nation program, National Public Radio, 2003 May 7 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c22_a_0011177
  - Iris Chang interview, KPFA radio, Berkeley, California, 2003 May 28 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c22_a_0011178
  - "The Chinese in America: Iris Chang," WILL radio, Urbana, Illinois, 2003 May 19 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    One CD sound disc. This disc is unreadable, either because no data was ever written to it or because the data has become corrupted.
  - "Iris Chang on Up Front,", 2003 May 30 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    Use copy reference number: 2004c22_a_0011179
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History, New York, 2003
    - Research materials
      - Photocopies of diaries, 1873-1891 (Box-folder 6: 12-15)
      - Interview transcripts, 1980-1995 (Box-folder 7: 1-5)
      - Photocopies of diaries, 1873-1879 (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
      - General, 1885-1999 (Box-folder 8: 3-5)
      - General, 1885-1999 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
    - Book tour, 2004 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Thread of the Silkworm, New York, 1995
    - Research materials, 1949-1996 (Box-folder 9: 4-5)
- Sound recordings
  - "China in the American Imagination," presentation by Iris Chang, Los Angeles Times Festival of Books, Los Angeles, California, 2004 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    One compact sound cassette and related correspondence
  - Iris Chang interview, Glenn Mitchell show, KERA radio, Dallas, Texas, 2004 March 29 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Iris Chang interview, Marc Steiner show, WYPR radio, 2004 April 15 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Iris Chang interview, The Spoken Word program, Public Radio South, 2004 (Box-folder 10: 4)
- Subject file
  - Chinese from Vietnam, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Golden Dragon massacre, 2000 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Taiwan, 1981-1999 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Chinatown gang--Bill Lee, 1999 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Nationalist soldiers in the U.S., 1988-1998 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - Yen, Rita, 1982 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Liu, Henry, 1993 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Drumright report, 1955-2001 (Box-folder 10: 12-13)
  - China Lobby, 1975-1998 (Box-folder 10: 14)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - Committee of 100, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 11: 1-3)
  - General, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 11: 4)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Thread of the Silkworm, New York, 1995
    - Research materials, 1950-1996 (Box-folder 11: 5-6)
- Writings by others
  - Meagher, Arnold J., undated (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
  - Qi, Shouhua, 2003 (Box-folder 12: 4-6)
  - Lu, Suping, 2003 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Landas, Marc, 2003 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Djao, Wei, 2002 (Box-folder 13: 3-4)
  - Li, Peter, 2002 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Miller, Donald L., 2001 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Hodges, Graham Russell Gao, 2003 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Fuller, Sherri Gebert, 2003 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Mitter, Rana, 2003 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Barenblatt, Daniel, 2003 (Box-folder 14: 5)
- Subject file
  - Chinese "ethnoburbs,", 1999 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - U.S. Census, 2000 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Chinese students in U.S.--1990s, 1991-2000 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - H-1B visa, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Tiananmen Square, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Taizi (princelings), 1992-1997 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Li Ka-shing family, 2000 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Astronaut family, 1999 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Parachute kids, 1994-1999 (Box-folder 15: 9)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History
    - Proofs, circa 2003 (Box-folder 16: 1-4)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies, 1897-1999 (Box-folder 16: 5-6)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies, 1897-1999 (Box-folder 17: 1-5)
    - Research materials, consisting primarily of photocopies, 1897-1997 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - Proofs, 2003 (Box-folder 18: 2-5)
- Correspondence, invitations, and printed matter
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History
    - Proofs, 2003 (Box-folder 19: 1-4)
    - Chinese American Forum, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - General, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 19: 6)
- Subject file
  - Political fundraising scandal, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Lucent arrests, 2001 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Lee, Peter, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Cox report, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - Chin, Larry Wu-tai, 1985-1999 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Espionage fears, 1985 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Spy plane collision, 2001 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Civil rights for Asian Americans, 1992-2000 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Sino-U.S. relations, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - Anti-immigration activism, 2000 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Blue team, 2000 (Box-folder 20: 11)
  - NATO strike of embassy, 1999 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - Detained Chinese Americans in People's Republic of China, 2001 (Box-folder 20: 13)
  - Glass ceiling issues, 1999 (Box-folder 20: 14)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History
    - Research materials
      - Photocopies of Immigration and Naturalization Service records, 1946-1999 (Box-folder 21: 1-2)
      - UCLA Asian American Studies Center search requests, 1999 (Box-folder 21: 3)
      - Photocopies of Gum Moon Women's Residence documents and correspondence, 1903-1999 (Box-folder 21: 4)
      - Chinese Historical Society of San Francisco bulletins and correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 21: 5)
      - Museum of Chinese American History newsletters and correspondence, 1999 (Box-folder 21: 6)
      - Dissertation lists, 1999 (Box-folder 21: 7)
      - Photocopies of immigration and census data, 1945-1997 (Box-folder 22: 1-3)
      - Museum of Chinese in the Americas correspondence and documents, 1999 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    - Photographs and captions, 2002 (Box-folder 22: 5-7)
- Subject file
  - "Separate Lives, Broken Dreams,", 1993 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - London, Jack, 1912 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    Photocopy of book excerpt.
  - Search for roots, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - Chinese question, 1877-1878 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    Photocopies of monograph excerpts.
  - Chinese in Los Angeles, 1997 (Box-folder 23: 5)
  - Chinese in Midwest, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - Chinese in Mexico, 1980-1999 (Box-folder 23: 7)
  - Chinese in Buffalo, 1991 (Box-folder 23: 8)
  - Chinese dissident scientists, undated (Box-folder 23: 9)
  - Chinese-American politicians, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 23: 10)
  - Chinese-American ministers, 2002 (Box-folder 23: 11)
  - Chinese-American designers, 1999 (Box-folder 23: 12)
  - Chinese-American broadcasters, 1999 (Box-folder 23: 13)
  - Chinese-American astronauts, 1999 (Box-folder 23: 14)
  - Asian-American film, 1989-2001 (Box-folder 23: 15)
  - Wang, David, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 24: 1-2)
  - Wang, Charles B., 1996-1999 (Box-folder 24: 3-4)
- Videorecordings
  - "Separate Lives, Broken Dreams,", 1993 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - "Charles B. Wang on Pinnacle,", undated (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - "The Yahoo! Story,", undated (Box-folder 25: 1)
- Subject file
  - Wu, Harry, 1996 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Woods, Tiger, 1997 (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Woo, Charles, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - Woo, John, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 25: 5)
  - Wong, Cy, 1988-2002 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - Yung Wing family, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 25: 7)
  - Wang, Wayne, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 25: 8)
  - Wang, K. L., 1997-2000 (Box-folder 25: 9)
  - Wang, L. Ling-Chi, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 25: 10-11)
  - Wang, Ying-lai, 2001 (Box-folder 26: 1)
  - Yee, John, 1981-2002 (Box-folder 26: 2)
  - Yao, Cynthia, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 26: 3)
  - Joe, Ray W., 2000 (Box-folder 26: 4)
  - Lee, David, 1989-2001 (Box-folder 26: 5)
  - Lee, Corky, 1999 (Box-folder 26: 6)
  - Kwan, Michelle, 2002 (Box-folder 26: 7)
  - Koo, George, 2001 (Box-folder 26: 8)
  - Hong, You Chung, 1999 (Box-folder 26: 9)
  - Haw, Tommy, 2000 (Box-folder 26: 10)
  - Fugh, John, 2000 (Box-folder 26: 11)
  - Wong, Chin Foo, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - Fong, Kenneth, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 26: 13)
  - Yee, Fung Chung, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 26: 14)
- Videorecordings
  - "Becoming American: The Chinese Experience in the Capital Region,", 2003 March (Box-folder 26: 15)
  - "When the Past Meets the Present," speech by Bill Moyers, Committee of 100 meeting, undated (Box-folder 26: 16)
- Subject file
  - Franking, Mae and Tiam, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Chuck, Frank, 1999 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - Chew, William, 1979-2001 (Box-folder 27: 3)
  - Chu, Betty, undated (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Chew, Thomas Foon, 2001 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - Chen, Winston, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Chen, John, 1999 (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Chen, Joan, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - Chang, Min Chueh, 1988-2000 (Box-folder 27: 9)
  - Chang, Leslie, 1999 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  - Chan, Ronnie, 1999 (Box-folder 27: 11)
  - Ark, Wong Kim, 1998 (Box-folder 27: 12)
  - Sung, C. B., 1998 (Box-folder 27: 13)
  - Chang, Gareth, 1999 (Box-folder 27: 14)
- Videorecording, "Adrift without Roots," film by Maria L. Gee, undated (Box-folder 28: 1)
  Four DVDs in one case
- Subject file
  - Sie, John J., 1991-1999 (Box-folder 28: 2)
  - Lee, Yan Phou, 1995 (Box-folder 28: 3)
  - Yang, Chen Ning, 1989 (Box-folder 28: 4)
  - Moy family, 1998 (Box-folder 28: 5)
  - Ling, Lisa, 2000 (Box-folder 28: 6)
  - Lin, T. Y., 1974-1999 (Box-folder 28: 7)
  - Lin, Maya, 2000 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  - Li, Portia, 2001 (Box-folder 28: 9)
  - Lew, Ronald, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 28: 10)
  - Lee, Lester, 2000 (Box-folder 28: 11)
  - Lee, Harry, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 28: 12)
  - Tu, John and David Sun, 1999 (Box-folder 28: 13)
  - Tsai, Gerald, Jr., 1999 (Box-folder 28: 14)
  - Tien, Chang-Lin, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 28: 15)
- Writings by others
  - Thompson, Robert Smith, 2001 (Box-folder 29: 1-3)
  - Tsu, C. N., 1997 (Box-folder 29: 4)
  - Bradley, James, 2003 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Guinn, Jeff, 2002 (Box-folder 30: 2-3)
  - Evans, Karin, 1999 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Hu, Hua-ling, 2000 (Box-folder 31: 2-3)
  - Maguire, Peter, 2000 (Box-folder 31: 4-5)
  - Ye, Zhaoyan, 2001 (Box-folder 32: 1-3)
  - Terrill, Ross, 2002 (Box-folder 32: 4)
- Awards and memorabilia
  - Certificate of honor, Board of Supervisors, City and County of San Francisco, California, 2003 October 4 (Box-folder 32: 5)
- Open (Box 33)
- Awards and memorabilia
  - "The 100 Most Influential Asian Americans of the Decade," award plaque from A. Magazine, 1999 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Award plaque, M Society West Aspire '99, San Francisco, California, 1999 May 28-31 (Box-folder 34: 2)
  - Award plaque, Committee of 100, 10th anniversary conference, 1999 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - Membership plaque, Committee of 100, 1998 (Box-folder 34: 4)
  - Award plaque, 1998 National Woman of the Year, Organization of Chinese American Women, Bethesda, Maryland, 1998 May 3 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Award plaque, Award for Excellence in Literature, Asian Business League of San Francisco, San Francisco, California, 2003 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - Guest of honor ribbon and name tag, Asian Business League of San Francisco, San Francisco, California, 2003 (Box-folder 34: 7)
  - Award plaque, "Rape of Nanking" Redress Coalition of Northern California, international conference, San Francisco, California, 2001 September 6-9 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - Award plaque, Outstanding Service Award, Truth Council for World War Two in Asia, Inc., Washington, D.C., 2003 May 7 (Box-folder 35: 2)
  - Award plaque, Association of Preserving the History of WWII in Asia (AOHWA), Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1998 April 4 (Box-folder 35: 3)
  - Award plaque, Toronto Association for Learning and Preserving the History of WWII in Asia (Toronto ALPHA), Toronto, Canada, 1997 December 13 (Box-folder 35: 4)
  - "History Makers" medal with frame, Friends of the Museum of Chinese American History, Los Angeles, California, 1996 October (Box-folder 35: 5)
  - Commemorative medal, Litquake 2003 (Box-folder 35: 6)
  - Satchel and notebook with name patch, Ohio Army National Guard, undated (Box-folder 35: 7)
- Oversize materials
  - One pen-and-ink drawing of a woman's face and Chinese dragon, undated (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Three copies of a poster advertising a book signing appearance by Iris Chang, 2003 April 23 (Box-folder 36: 2-4)
  - Four posters produced by the Bataan Commemorative Research Project, Proviso Township High Schools, Maywood-Hillside, Illinois, 2000 (Box-folder 36: 5-8)
  - Operation Recognition poster, Proviso Township High Schools, undated (Box-folder 36: 9)
- Open (Boxes 37-105)
- Rolodex address files, Two cubic foot boxes (Boxes 106-107)
- Business cards and addresses
  - Chinese-American business people, undated (Box-folder 108: 1-2)
  - Academia, undated (Box-folder 108: 3)
  - Services, undated (Box-folder 108: 4)
  - General, undated (Box-folder 108: 5-7)
  - American tour, 2003 (Box-folder 109: 1-2)
  - Defunct cards, undated (Box-folder 109: 3)
  - Non-Chinese readers, undated (Box-folder 109: 4)
  - Chinese language, undated (Box-folder 109: 5)
  - Academia, undated (Box-folder 109: 6)
  - General, undated (Box-folder 110: 1-2)
  - Book publishers, undated (Box-folder 110: 3)
  - Bookstores, undated (Box-folder 110: 4)
  - Hollywood, undated (Box-folder 110: 5)
  - Civic organizations, undated (Box-folder 110: 6)
  - Political activists, undated
    - Japan (Box-folder 110: 7)
    - Taiwan (Box-folder 110: 8)
    - United States (Box-folder 110: 9)
    - Canada (Box-folder 110: 10)
    - Hong Kong (Box-folder 110: 11)
    - Korea (Box-folder 110: 12)
  - Oral histories, undated (Box-folder 111: 1)
  - Personal services, undated (Box-folder 111: 2)
  - Authors, undated (Box-folder 111: 3)
  - Seminar speakers, undated (Box-folder 111: 4)
  - Media, undated
    - Asia (Box-folder 111: 5)
    - Canada (Box-folder 111: 6)
    - United States (Box-folder 111: 7-9)
- Note cards relating to writings by Iris Chang, undated
  - Thread of the Silkworm (Box-folder 112: 1-10)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II (Box-folder 113: 1-10)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II (Box-folder 114: 1-10)
  - The Rape of Nanking: The Forgotten Holocaust of World War II (Box-folder 115: 1-10)
  - Thread of the Silkworm (Box-folder 116: 1-10)
  - Thread of the Silkworm (Box-folder 117: 1-10)
  - Personal thoughts (Box-folder 118: 1-10)
  - "Turning Back the Biological Clock: The Fertility Revolution that is Redefining Power between Men and Women" (Box-folder 119: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 120: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 121: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 122: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 123: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 124: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 125: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 126: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 127: 1-10)
  - The Chinese in America: A Narrative History (Box-folder 128: 1-10)
- Biographical file
  - Curriculum vitae, undated (Box-folder 129: 1)
  - Primary and secondary school publications, 1970-1984 (Box-folder 129: 2-6)
  - Report cards, 1976-1984 (Box-folder 129: 7)
  - Correspondence relating to high school application, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 129: 8)
  - Autograph book, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 129: 9)
- Speeches and writings by Iris Chang
  - Diary entry, 1998 (Box-folder 130: 1)
  - Newspaper articles, including reprints
    Includes some correspondence relating to articles.
    - General, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 130: 2)
    - Chicago Tribune, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 130: 3-4)
    - Daily Illini, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 130: 5)
    - New York Times, 1989 (Box-folder 130: 6)
    - Associated Press, 1989 (Box-folder 130: 7)
    - Campus Voice, 1988 (Box-folder 130: 8-9)
- Biographical file
  - School certificate, 1978 (Box-folder 131: 1)
  - Instructional materials for Chinese class, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 131: 2-3)
  - Composition book used for Chinese class, 1974 (Box-folder 131: 4)